we transitioned into what has become a
permanent wartime economy every
president For Better or Worse wants to
be a wartime President right that's how
you enter the history books I guess
selling defense is a maybe an easy thing
to do for humans because you can
introduce fear or uncertainty and it's
maybe the perfect business model so how
does this end John I'm not sure how it
ends short of the most devastating
recession or depression in American
history that forces us to reassess our
priorities
Americans is you always offer US
democracy and military aid and the
Chinese offer us food and New Roads and
the next thing you know the Chinese have
bases all over Africa and in Washington
here at the state department they ask
themselves how did that happen just do
what the Chinese are doing and stop
spending so much money on unnecessary
defense expenditures I need to hear a
little bit about your personal story you
were on the line you saw that torture
program you mentioned that Cheney was in
that room there and then I guess you saw
kind of things that went into place the
way I made a real name for myself at the
agency was the capture of Abu zubaida
who was the number three in Al Qaeda and
catching him that night literally
changed the course of the rest of my
life for better for worse mostly for
worse because that's when they wanted to
torture him and that's when you drew the
line yeah I said guys have none of you
Geneva Convention we can't do that it's
a war crime you know they call you the
human rights guy and I said yeah I know
that and he said you know that's not a
compliment right
and I said Steve I'm right and they're
wrong
and that's what's gonna come out at the
end
[Music]
the world is changing
inspiration is everywhere
it has never been so easy to connect
share and bring people together
we're learning from others and finding
the best in ourselves
[Music]
challenging our beliefs
sharing our vulnerability
overcoming our fears
transforming ourselves
so we can transform the world
how far can we go
this is London reel I am Brian Rose my
guest today is
[Music]
this is London real I am Brian Rose my
guest today is John kiriaku the former
CIA officer counter-terrorism expert
author and whistleblower you work for
the CIA from 1990 to 2004 notably as the
chief of counter-terrorist operations in
Pakistan due to the 9 11 Terror attacks
here you refuse to participate in the
training of enhanced interrogation
techniques later identified as a torture
program in 2009 with an interview with
ABC you became the first former
government official to confirm the use
of waterboarding against Al-Qaeda
suspects and in 2012 you were charged
with leaking classified information to
journalists and sentenced to 30 months
in prison as a result you lost
friendships your job and were vilified
in the mainstream Press today you focus
on fighting for human rights and
supporting those that face similar
consequences and you ultimately believe
there are things we should never do even
in the name of National Security and the
US government should stop participating
in immoral and unethical practices John
welcome to londonreal
thank you so much for having me it's a
pleasure looking forward to jumping into
it I think you once said I'm a patriot I
love my country I want it to succeed but
I think it's making a lot of mistakes
and I'd love to get your opinion on kind
of what's happening in the world I think
I'll start off with a situation that's
close to home over here and that's the
war in Ukraine and I was just wondering
what is your what is your take on what's
happening there we're what 500 some days
into it the US is pumping tons of money
tons of weapons into that we recently
saw this Wagner quote-unquote coup
happen you know you work for the Sputnik
radio and so maybe you know a few things
about Russia that we don't what is your
take on the situation as we see it now
popular either at work or amongst my
friends my position is look if we're
going to be supporters of Peace then we
have to be supporters of peace I
understand why the Russian government
took the decision to enter Ukraine I
understand that the United States was
behind a coup a soft coup in 2014 but if
we're going to be peace next then we
have to oppose
War period and so on on the day of the
invasion
I sat on my radio show which is on
Sputnik radio here in Washington it's a
Russian government-owned radio network I
said at the start of the show I
unequivocally oppose the Russian
invasion of Ukraine and I urge Russian
troops to leave Ukraine immediately with
that said I equally strongly oppose U.S
and NATO intervention in Ukraine we told
the the the Russian government
repeatedly and I'm talking about
uh president uh uh Bill Clinton
president Barack Obama we told them
repeatedly that we would not support
Ukrainian membership in NATO and we
never meant that we we were lying to
them to placate them
and so knowing that that was a Russian
Redline we did it anyway and we started
talking to the Ukrainian government
about entering NATO we promised the
Russian government that we would not
allow NATO to expand to its borders and
we did repeatedly with the Baltic states
for example and Poland
still to then point the finger at the
Russians and say this is this is all the
result of Russian hegemony of Russian
imperialism is disingenuous
I think at the very least everybody
should be sitting at the table and we
should be trying to negotiate a
settlement to this thing
why do you think the the Biden
Administration has seemed to go kind of
all in on this War I mean is it
something as simple as you know it's
easy to get reelected in Wartime a
matter of fact I think there's almost
like 100 correlation or is it much
deeper because they've really grabbed on
to this and you know if it seems like
one of their core platforms is that we
are fighting for whatever reasons and
we're going to take this all the way
um not always the party of war in the
past and just yeah curious on why you
think they did that and was it obvious
they would do that from the start
I think that's a very important question
and I think the answer
is several fold number one yes you're
correct I think this was a strategic
re-election move
um
number two and I don't mean to sound
cynical but I really believe this I
think that Joe Biden like every other
president uh is constantly thinking
about his legacy every president For
Better or Worse wants to be a wartime
President right that's how you enter the
history books is as a wartime president
and uh you know we were we were pulling
out of Afghanistan after two decades
we're pulling out of Iraq after nearly
two decades uh
what better way to make a name for
yourself for generations to come than to
take on one of the world's greatest
Powers in Russia and to do it for what
you say is is the right reasons so I
think that's a part of it as well
um and you know one of the things that's
that's utterly perplexing to me is what
you've just alluded to and that is the
flip that we've seen in the Democratic
party where the Democratic party used to
used to lead demonstrations in the
streets in opposition for example to uh
the Vietnam War it was the Democrats who
came out uh in opposition to the little
tiny mini war that we had in Grenada in
the early uh 1980s the only opposition
to the first Gulf War was among a
handful of Democratic senators uh it was
it was only Democrats that opposed the
second year Iraq War
well what what happened why are the
Democrats all in and and they're all in
without giving long-term thought to how
exactly we're going to pay for all this
and what does Victory look like nobody's
ever nobody's ever actually Quantified
what that's going to be at what point do
we declare Victory and go home is it the
utter defeat of the Russian military
because that's never going to happen the
Russian military is 20 times the size of
the Ukrainian military and it has
nuclear weapons
so again what is Victory I think we
should begin to temper our expectations
and whether we like it at this early
stage or not get everybody to the
negotiating table
yeah what does Victory look like I think
I was I had Colonel uh McGregor on a
couple weeks ago I think he brought that
yeah he's great yeah he's fantastic he
brought that same question up and you
know you've heard it so many times
throughout history you asked that
question about Vietnam you asked that
question about Iraq you asked the
question about Afghanistan so many
people have openly asked it and yes
right now here we are and they're like
what the hell does Victory look like you
know what I bet you couldn't even get an
answer from that out of out of DC and
you've got the Republican side people
like Donald Trump which I guess 10 years
ago you'd think this guy of course he
would want war you know he's saying the
crazy thing is both Donald Trump and RFK
and I you I know you've had
conversations with him and we have as
well they both said I could end this war
with a phone call and it's old right
first of all do you think that's true
John do you think both of those guys
could end it with a phone call
that's a tough one
um
uh perhaps I hate to be wishy-washy I
apologize for that uh it's it's possible
first of all let me say Doug Doug
McGregor's a dear friend of mine and I
have absolutely deep respect uh for not
just his his knowledge and understanding
of these complex issues but for his
willingness to go out on a limb even
when his positions are unpopular we need
more people like that in Washington not
fewer you know Doug was supposed to be
the U.S ambassador to Germany and the
Republicans blocked his nomination now
how ridiculous is that I don't want to
get too far off topic but
uh yeah I suppose it it would be popular
if the Russian side were were able to
trust an American leader and I think
that they would trust Donald Trump and
Bob Kennedy on this issue
I think that could lead to some sort of
a of a settlement and how ironic is it
how odd is it that it's the Republicans
who have begun saying look we can't
afford this over the long term this is
not a cost that the American taxpayers
should bear this is not a war that we
need to be involved in it's a war of
choice why aren't the Democrats saying
that why do we have the likes of of
Alexandria ocasio-cortez supporting
um supporting Appropriations for
continued war or Bernie Sanders or
Elizabeth Warren I just don't understand
the rule reversal that we've seen in
this war it it doesn't make any kind of
sense to me
yeah and meanwhile there's like hundreds
of thousands of ukrainians dying there's
tons of money being pumped in and I want
to ask you about your theories on the
wartime economy because it's it's it it
bring it comes up here for sure and then
on top of that I don't know what you see
in America but here in the UK you see a
massive mainstream media bias towards
Ukraine oh my God I mean oh it's
ridiculous it's ridiculous and I pull up
the guardian and the times and then I
look at the New York Times sometimes
occasionally I still do and I just look
at it and I'm just like guys I mean if
there's any tiny little bit of Victory
they magnify it from the ukrainians and
if there's any tiny slip in the in the
Russians they magnify it luckily I get
to talk to like guys like Jim Rickards
and Colonel McGregor and they're like
look this is not the truth on the ground
and if you know that you look at the
media and even the media can't sell me
on it so why do you think that's
happening and what do you see do you see
the same thing
oh I absolutely see the same thing and
the worst offenders are the New York
Times in the Washington Post
you just can't trust uh coverage in the
New York Times The Washington Post like
you said they'll take the smallest
setback on the part of the Russians and
blow it up to you know the end of the
wars at hand
they'll take the the smallest Victory by
the ukrainians and say that you know
this is David and Goliath I I can't tell
you how many times I've seen that
analogy uh in fact
when the ukrainians had set out to uh to
begin the counter-offensive which was
actually several weeks late uh it was
the Ukrainian military that predicted
that by this point in the summer they
would have moved 60 miles inside Russian
territory and they would have divided
the Russian military into two in Crimea
in fact here we are months after the
start of the counter offensive they've
moved five miles uh inside Russian
territory they're nowhere near Crimea
and they have not split the Russian
military
well that's
that's the loss
that's not a victory
but what was the banner headline on the
New York Times today it was an analysis
of how uh Vladimir Putin was almost
overthrown in what they're now calling
the Wagner Coupe there was no Wagner
coup
it just never happened it was it was an
ill-fated uh March a third of the way to
Moscow that the Russian government was
able to negotiate out of and the leader
of this coup attempt has been has been
exiled
so rather than to focus on made up
patriotic uh uh falsities
why don't we tell the truth
the real truth and and courage and end
this conflict why do the major outlets
in the American Media have to be
cheerleaders for American government
policy that just doesn't make any sense
to me it hasn't been like that in the
past at least not to this degree but
this is what we're up against where you
just can't find Reliable news
yeah I've had Seymour hershon here who
used to work for the Times And now when
he comes out with his theory on the
Nordstrom bombing which I might get your
thoughts on you know they won't even
talk or print what he's referring to and
they they make some other story up and
like you know you spent time a lot of
time in the CIA and you know about
psyops and you know about surveillance
when you look at the New York Times like
how how do you explain that to yourself
like is there someone at the top that
just says we take the the you know the
the left narrative and we magnify it it
can't be that simple or do they really
believe in what they're doing no it's
not that simple okay uh yeah they do
believe in what they're doing and you
know what I'm going to answer your
question with a with a short story
uh my last job at CIA headquarters was
as
um the executive assistant to the cia's
deputy director for operations very
important job access to literally
everything and long hard hours so I had
uh I had hit a lull in my day my boss
was off in a meeting and I kind of
kicked back in my chair like this and I
was looking out into the hallway
and I was just relaxing momentarily
looking out into the hallway and Bob
Woodward walked past it my office Bob
Woodward being the the famed acclaimed
Washington Post uh senior investigative
report
and my brain didn't believe what my eyes
had seen so I said to the secretary hey
was that Bob Woodward that just walked
past the office and she said yeah
I said
without a security expert ex escort Bob
Woodward is just walking the halls of
CIA headquarters
and she said oh you didn't see the
director's email
and I said no
she said yeah uh they gave him free
reign he's writing a book and and we've
all been ordered to cooperate with him
well I I refused I mean like one of the
holy of holies at the CIA is that you
never ever talk to the media for any
reason well I came to learn that of
course you talk to the media when you
know the media are willing to carry your
water for you
you know exactly who to leak to and who
you're going to lead to
are Bob Woodward at the Washington Post
Joby Warwick at the post
um uh David Ignatius at the post and a
half a dozen people at the New York
Times
and then there are a couple of other
people you know NBC News and the LA
Times and Wolf Blitzer at CNN uh because
they're going to report exactly what you
want them to report
so it's it's not as clear-cut as as most
Americans believe I'll give you another
example I was only on the job for a
couple of weeks this was in 1990 and um
and I saw Wolf Blitzer Walking The Halls
with a camera crew no less and no
security escort and he was doing a
stand-up with his microphone right in
front of a sign that said CIA uh
historical intelligence collection it
was a an offshoot of the CIA library and
I don't remember looking at him and just
shaking my head as I was walking out
like well somebody ought to be arrested
for this
probably Wolf Blitzer and the CIA
security person who's not escorting him
right now and I I walked out
but this kind of thing happens all the
time you know they we like to think that
there's this Chinese wall between uh the
CIA and especially senior Cia officers
and the American Media and in fact
they're in bed together
wow wow and it was funny because I
talked to see more about his theory on
the North stream bombing and then a
couple weeks later I saw the New York
Times article again with this when you
hear the details that Seymour gives you
and then you see the New York Times
article it was this wacky theory about
some bulgarians that rented a boat and
went down there and I was just like look
I've never spent any time in CIA
headquarters but it didn't take an
expert to realize that story sounded it
sounded like somebody fed it to them and
they just printed it up just to satisfy
some things and just keep it moving and
it was just had a bunch of holes in it
even I could see from one hour with
Seymour so
um but I guess the American public
doesn't really know any better they read
it they keep moving on and so this is a
psyops that works you fool most of the
people most of the time and so it
proceeds
one of my closest friends uh used to be
a boss of mine when I was on a two-year
rotation to the state department so he's
a very senior former State Department
official in fact I'm going to have
dinner with him tonight and um when uh
this explosion took place on the
nordstrain pipeline
um
I called him and I said I said we we had
to have done this right I mean it
couldn't be anybody else it had to be us
and he said no no the Russians did it
and I said you think the Russians blew
up their own pipeline what what could
they possibly have to gain by blowing up
their own pipeline well he said it would
be embarrassing for us
I said Don with all due respect that
doesn't make any kind of sense at all
and I talked to cyhurst about it and I
said uh I said this was us right and he
said well it could be us it could be the
uh the ukrainians and I said yeah if the
ukrainians had a mini sub that would
allow them to go down there but do they
even have that kind of technology I mean
we're the only ones that have that kind
of technology that I know of when I say
we I mean the United States and NATO I
just don't get what anybody else on the
other side would have to gain from
something like this and sure enough Psy
was mostly right uh if it wasn't us it
was the ukrainians we all suspected it
uh even though the mainstream media
doesn't want to actually come out and
say it and let me add something about
cyhurst too you know this is a guy
this is a guy who for the last 60 years
has been one of the most highly honored
highly awarded uh journalists uh in in
America the guy was was the definition
of investigative journalism in the
second half of the 20th century
and he literally cannot get published
anymore uh I'm a member of a group
called veteran intelligence
Professionals for sanity it's a group of
of retirees from the CIA the FBI NSA and
and the U.S military and we give an
award every year called the the Sam
Adams award for integrity in
intelligence we gave the award to Psy in
2017 and he complained that that he was
under such pressure from the mainstream
media here in the United States that the
only place he could get his pieces
published was in the London Review of
Books which is great it's highly
respected but nobody reads the London
Review of Books they might have a few
thousand subscribers
now here we are five years later and he
can't even get himself published in the
London Review of Books and so he's had
to take to sub stack to publish himself
and to get the truth out there that's
how bad things have gotten here in the
United States yeah if there was ever a
perfect example it's that I mean again
look at what he did with My Lai Massacre
I mean this is exactly I mean this is a
guy who had
you know he's shown that he has a
commitment to like to journalism and to
Integrity enough to where you know he
was hated and vilified by the military
but he brings that same ethics to what
he's doing today and now that these same
Publications won't touch him and it's
like he Psy hasn't changed the media
happens right oh you're exactly right
yeah the media has changed we've changed
as Americans but can you imagine for
example
the United States ever being able able
to point to someone some media figure
and say you know what he's the new
Walter Cronkite
Walter cronkite's dead and gone there
will never be another Walter Cronkite
there will there will never be another
media figure that a majority of
Americans has respect for to the point
where
every four years people say you know
what would be really great is if Walter
Cronkite would run for president that
will never ever happen again never
wow because there's nobody with that
type of Integrity in that space anymore
yeah that person doesn't exist it's uh
it's it's it's a brand new world I guess
at least we could see it happening you
know with people like PSY and I know
he's had some success on on substack
which is great and uh I always love
talking to him he's uh he's my only
guest that uh that rocks in a rocking
chair while he talks and uh and it
doesn't matter because everyone watches
him so um yeah Luca's great to see just
to finish how do you think this plays
out with Russia like what do you think
happens especially if you take it all
the way up to the election
at the CIA in our analysis we used to
use this term all the time muddling
through
um you know so many so many people just
naturally their brain defaults to an
either or uh uh Choice uh when they when
they try to prognosticate and oftentimes
what was true was that the parties in
the conflict just sort of muddled
through and things just didn't change
over the medium term and I think that
that's what we're looking at here the
Russians aren't gonna aren't going to
use nuclear weapons I don't think
they'll even use tactical nuclear
weapons because they'll lose the
propaganda advantage of saying look the
only country in the history of the
planet that's ever used nuclear weapons
is the United States and they did it
twice
right they don't want to be lumped in
with that they want to be able to
continue to point at the United States
like they've done since 1945.
um they don't need to use nuclear
weapons even tactical ones uh now they
have a virtually Unlimited Supply of of
suicide drones that they're getting from
both the Chinese and the Iranians and
are attempting to purchase from the from
the Indians and so what's better than a
small payload on a on a drone that costs
you fourteen thousand dollars rather
than the you know 100 000 or 200 000
that American missiles cost and you can
just lob them into buildings or into
military bases or onto airfields I think
that they're just going to continue to
do that I think we'll see a slight
upgrade in the level of uh of Russian
technology that they're able to either
develop or to purchase on the open
market I think that here in the United
States will continue to arm and and to
train the ukrainians in
basically whatever they want
up to and including the F-16
and then I think as we approach the
American elections
the Republicans are going to have a real
campaign issue uh going home and saying
why should we be paying for all this we
have bridges falling into the rivers
below them we have international
airports that are international
embarrassments for anybody who's ever
traveled around the world we have an
interstate highway system that would
take a trillion dollars to repair
and we want to move the world's
microchip manufacturing out of uh out of
Taiwan and Singapore and into Ohio and
uh and Arizona
with what money
with the money that we're sending to to
Ukraine this has to come to a stop
and God knows already our our NATO
allies don't want to pay for it they're
they're uh their National debts as a as
a function of GDP are worse than ours
they want us to pay for it and so I
think we'll we'll muddle through the
short term and maybe the medium term and
then it's going to become a political
issue here in the United States where
where American voters just say look
enough enough with this we don't want to
pay for it anymore this has to be
settled and I think eventually it will
be you know we a lot of us said this at
the very beginning too and I I should
repeat this
um I think in the end
the Russians are going to keep uh
Donetsk and luhansk they're going to
keep the Crimea
there will be a promise that Ukraine
will not join NATO
but the United States will declare
Ukraine a major non-nato Ally like
Israel or Japan or Bahrain or Saudi
Arabia
and uh Ukraine will be fast tracked for
membership in the European Union I think
that's how this ends hmm
hmm and do you think this could lose the
abide in the re-election or do you think
with all the propaganda going on it will
not be a major enough issue for people
to say enough is enough
I don't think it'll be enough of an
issue I think it's going to drag on
longer than that I think it's going to
drag on through the election now if Joe
Biden were able to run for for election
again in 2028 which of course he's not
even if he were to be alive in 2028
um I think by 2028 everybody's going to
be sick of this but I think 2024 is
practically upon us and
you know look look around I I'm I'm
looking over for example uh right now as
we speak
not McPherson Square but uh but Farragut
Square I'm one block from the White
House and we're not seeing people in the
streets we're not seeing people marching
with signs and placards saying you know
end the war we're not people are just
going about their normal business like
they generally don't care
because it doesn't affect them directly
but when we have to
keep raising taxes
to pay for these weapon systems and all
this money goes to U.S defense
contractors and they get rich while you
and I get poor
and we continue to neglect our
infrastructure
then finally I think people are going to
get sick of this well let's talk about
that John because this is this is kind
of Ip that's unique to you because I've
heard you say the following that if we
were not
at war or producing weapons for war we
would immediately go into a recession
and you've argued that's the case for
the past couple decades
um can you explain that position because
a lot of people would be surprised to
hear that
yeah I've been saying this for a little
while now in the immediate aftermath of
the 9 11 attacks uh we transitioned into
what has become a permanent wartime
economy pre-911
the wealthiest place in America was
Silicon Valley it had the most
millionaires per capita of anywhere in
the United States that is no longer true
now Washington DC is the wealthiest
place in America and it's because of the
trillions with a t trillions of dollars
that we have spent on the
military-industrial complex there are
literally thousands of Beltway Bandits
these are military and intelligence
Community contractors that ring the
capital Beltway that surrounds uh
Washington DC and now there are more
millionaires per capita in Washington DC
than there are anywhere else in America
it's because of 9 11 and it's because of
our government's commitment to spend
literally unlimited amounts of money on
what is deemed to be National Defense
well we've gotten so used to you know
sucking the the teat so to speak of the
American taxpayer
that we now can't shut off that flow of
money to these these Beltway Bandits
these defense contractors without
pushing the country into recession
that's how much money we're spending we
can't we can't move that money we can't
move those Appropriations to something
else
like
uh
transportation for example
or infrastructure or education or
the environment including the
environmental cleanup we just can't they
can't absorb those those gigantic
amounts of money it took us 20 years to
get where we are with defense you know
I'll add another thing and I I promise
not to throw too many uh statistics at
you but our defense budget is now bigger
than the next nine largest countries
combined
right you take China Germany the UK
France Japan the next nine largest
countries combined and we still spend
more
why
to prepare for what
to give free money to the ukrainians
or
money to uh these countries of the Sahel
no this is all supposed to be a big
secret but we're pumping billions of
dollars into Niger and Mali and Burkina
Faso and guinea conocry and guinea
bissau for what reason
the French problem why aren't the French
pumping their money into those countries
why does it always have to be us and why
is it a secret
don't the American taxpayers have the
right to know
where their money's going and to decide
if that's an appropriate expenditure I
would say yes
so there's no reason for us to be
spending this kind of money I'll tell
you something else too a couple of weeks
ago a policeman was shot in Paris shot
and severely wounded and the gun the
rifle that he was shot with was uh was
confiscated by the police and the serial
number on this rifle was an assault
rifle the serial number matched the
serial number from a shipment of assault
rifles that we had sent to Ukraine about
six months earlier how in the world
did that assault rifle come into the
possession of a criminal in Paris
I'll tell you because it had been sold
on the black market
so where's the oversight for these
billions and billions of dollars that
we're turning over to the ukrainians now
we're not just writing a check and
sending cash we've learned our lesson to
not do that we did that right from Iraq
right yeah we did it Iraq right
so we're we're writing these checks to
the defense contractors and the defense
contractors then send the equipment to
Ukraine well the equipment's then for
sale on the black market for pennies on
the dollar
why why do we permit that where is the
Congressional oversight and even not
even Congressional oversight where are
the inspectors General at DOD and CIA
and these other organizations that are
active on the ground there this is
really a a great vast disservice to the
American people wow so if enough
people's paychecks depend on it these
Beltway Bandits then it's just going to
happen because you can't shut down all
of their livelihoods so they're going to
find a way to make it happen it's like a
weird kind of a shadow government a bit
of momentum there and they'll use
whatever it takes to get there and I
guess selling more or selling defense is
a maybe an easy thing to do for humans
because you can introduce fear or
uncertainty and also I don't know how
many guns it takes to fight that scary
thing over there right yeah and so it's
maybe the perfect business model
oh my God yes you're exactly right it's
the perfect business model and you look
at some of these Appropriations votes I
don't mean to smile I mean I'm smiling I
guess ironically you look at these
Appropriations those and you have some
of the most conservative
bible-beating members of Congress
joining hands with the most liberal
Democratic Socialist members of Congress
and voting yes on these budgets because
they represent this area and the excerbs
of Washington DC and that's what makes
Washington Recession Proof right there
will never be a recession in Washington
because the business of Washington is
government but it's not just government
it's government and it's what my former
CIA colleague Ray McGovern calls the
Mickey mat I I say the
military-industrial complex he says the
military industrial Congressional uh uh
I forget whatever else it's a whole list
of things complex that makes this city
run it's it's the lobbyists and it's the
defense contractors and it's the
consultants and it's the lobbyists
in addition to uh
to Congress and he's absolutely right
nobody is going to allow you to take
this away from them not after 20 years
of getting rich
it's it's no wonder now that this is one
of the most expensive real estate
markets in America now you know we used
to laugh
about markets like San Francisco and
Honolulu and Manhattan say my God I'm
glad I don't live there who could afford
to live there well now that's what our
prices are like in real estate and it's
because there are so many people who are
rich
that they can afford to buy houses at
these inflated prices because they're
the ones making this government money
wow wow and also I'm guessing if you're
a member of Congress or the Senate your
local constituency wherever it is has a
big chunk of their revenue probably
coming in from some type of Defense
contracts and so if you want to get
reelected first of all you want to be
supported by the lobbyists and then you
also want to make sure jobs aren't lost
and so it just becomes this flywheel and
everybody just lets it go
oh yeah you've hit that nail right on
the head uh and that's what happens even
by members of Congress who vote against
these Appropriations sure they'll vote
against the appropriation when they know
that their no votes not going to kill
the bill right and then they'll go back
home and say for every dollar
that we send to the federal government
in our taxes I bring in a dollar
Seventeen in uh in federal aid or in
Contracting from these uh these defense
contractors and people say well that's
great that's what congressional
representation is all about
it's it's like the perfect
handshake arrangement everybody's happy
everybody makes money and then the rest
of us when we realize what's been
happening right under our noses and it's
too late to do anything about it
so how does this end John or does yeah
you know I I'm not sure how it ends
short of the most devastating recession
or depression in American history that
forces us to reassess our priorities
you know there is no reason
none whatsoever why our military budget
should be we should be greater than the
next nine largest countries in the world
combined why did the Chinese for example
go all around the world buying ports and
airports and factories and building
roads in exchange for bonds and and
becoming the go-to superpower in places
like like Africa for example or all
across Asia why is that an African
Diplomat told me just recently he was
here with with his president
um for this White House Summit he said
you know the thing about you Americans
is you always offer US democracy and
military aid and the Chinese offer us
food and New Roads
so they go with the Chinese
they don't want democracy they can't
make democracy function anyway
and military aid we're going to give
that to them anyway because you know
terrorism got to stop terrorism
and so the Chinese go in and say well
listen we'll pave that road that you've
been wanting to to build from your
Capital City out to the hinterland and
all we ask in exchange is you give us
the international airport and then you
give us five billion dollars uh that you
repay over 30 years using treasury bonds
and they said hey that sounds like a
pretty darn good deal
and the next thing you know the Chinese
have bases all over Africa and in
Washington here at the state department
they ask themselves how did that happen
we didn't see that coming
yeah yeah it's what are they saying you
can catch more flies with honey than
with vinegar that's the expression right
well there's the expression about the
two bulls on the ridge the poppable and
the the young bull and the young bull
says the papabola let's run down and
[__] one of those cows and the papa Bowl
says no let's walk down and [__] them
all
and so it's America America right so is
that America America is this new country
you know we we we're aggressors maybe
America is an aggressive Nation anyways
and so we we do business one way and
then the Chinese are meanwhile thinking
maybe a thousand years out and saying
guess what we're gonna go in we're gonna
give them all everything they want and
then later maybe they can pay us in Yuan
later maybe they'll take our 5G
monitoring systems and then later maybe
they'll join our currency and they win
yeah
you're watching the rest of the episode
for free visit our website londonreal.tv
or click the link in the description
below
[Music]
so Jim Rickards has just recorded a
video that's not available to anyone in
the public and he's going to be talking
about how this upcoming recession is
going to be fast it's going to be bloody
it's going to be nasty but at the same
time he's going to show you how you can
position yourself to profit from all of
this chaos now we've made this video
only available to our viewers go to
londonreal@tv forward slash gym watch
that immediately I can't say enough good
things about Jim Rickards he understands
the global economic system better than
any guest I've ever had on London reel
his predictions are almost untannily
true and you can learn how to profit
from his vision from his expertise and
his understanding of Economics so go to
lunderville.tv forward slash gym or
click the link below it's an excellent
excellent look on what's going to happen
in the future and how you can position
yourself to profit from that Jim is one
of the best in the business one of my
favorite guests on London reel and he's
very very good
future and showing us all to profit from
it so click the link and I hope you
enjoy
hey it's Brian Rose founder of the D5
Academy I've told you my four week
crypto boot camp is amazing but don't
take my word for it this is what my
students are saying the D5 Academy was
an amazing experience for me
so in this course I was challenged I was
held accountable and pushed to do things
that honestly weren't always easy it's
been phenomenal and I can't believe uh
we're already up on our four weeks it
has flown by going through this D5
accelerator by far was one of the best
courses I've taken you do this course
you really get into the nitty-gritty of
the activities that will make you
comfortable with decentralized Finance
thank you so much to Brian and everyone
at londonreal and the D5 Academy for
even putting together an amazing course
like this everybody else that wants to
do it please sign up it is well worth
the money
thank you